WILLIFORD T. ABUNAS | Full Stack Software Developer

Visa: New Zealand Resident

Email: abunaswilliford@gmail.com | Phone: +64226332514

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/pocodev | Github: github.com/williford-abunas | Portfolio: https://williford-abunas.github.io

ABOUT ME

Greetings! I'm a former teacher who transitioned into full-stack software development. I've always been drawn to the tech side of teaching, especially educational technology.

This year, I made the decision to wholeheartedly embrace my fascination with information technology. Enrolling in the Dev Academy Aotearoa bootcamp was a transformative experience, where I discovered that my innate love for learning seamlessly aligned with the world of coding. Working collaboratively with diverse teams, solving bugs, and constantly exploring new approaches became a source of genuine enjoyment for me. The challenging journey into the tech world not only made it meaningful but also cultivated my love for overcoming challenges. Now armed with this experience, I am eagerly poised to apply my skills and contribute meaningfully to the ever-evolving tech landscape, driven by a passion for creating positive change and innovation.

EXPERIENCE

Dev Academy Aotearoa

Wellington, New Zealand 08/2023 - 12/2023

Full Stack Software Development Student

- A 15 week full immersion bootcamp, totalling 800 hours, involves working on multiple projects in a team environment.
- Applied HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, Relational Databases, Testing and RESTful APIs for personal and group projects.
- Integrated Agile methodologies (kanban boards, MVP, sprints, wireframes and roles) and Human skills (empathy, feedback, listening and looping, growth mindset, and conflict resolution) into projects.
- Worked on <u>Friendbooking</u> as our final project, an appointment application which involves using Date and Time picker components - an unexplored feature in our repertoire. I also served as Git lead, ensuring that code changes are tracked, documented, and merged effectively as well as addressing and resolving merge conflicts that may arise.

Dannevirke South School

Dannevirke, New Zealand 07/2022 - 07/2023

Primary School Teacher

- Worked collaboratively with colleagues to enhance overall learning experience for students.
- Incorporated educational technology to enhance learning experiences and prepare students for the digital age.
- Integrated culturally responsive practices into teaching. E.g. I shared my Filipino
 culture and discussed cultural differences to model identity pride, integrated
 cultural events into lessons and displayed artworks, symbols and artifacts
 representing their backgrounds.
- Engaged in ongoing professional development.

St. Peter's College

Palmerston North, New Zealand 03/2022 - 06/2022

Learning Support Assistant (Teacher Aide)

- Worked alongside and supported students with additional learning needs.
- Attended professional development sessions on the role.

Capiz State University – Pontevedra

Bailan, Pontevedra, Capiz, Philippines 09/2019 - 12/2021

College Instructor I (Tertiary)

- Developed and delivered lectures, workshops, and discussions based on the curriculum of the assigned courses.
- Collaborated with colleagues on curriculum development and other academic initiatives
- Administered assessments and provided timely and constructive feedback to students on their academic progress.
- Advised and mentored students on academic and career-related matters.
- Incorporated technology into teaching methods and designed distance online learning materials to facilitate learning during pandemic lockdowns.

Tanque National High School

Brgy. Tanque, Roxas City, Philippines 07/2013 - 09/2019

Secondary School Teacher III

- Taught Information and Communication Technologies(ICT), Humanities and Social Sciences subjects.
- Served as ICT Coordinator, training teachers on educational technologies, and managed school ICT inventory. I also made digital assets for school promotion.
- Promoted from Teacher I to Teacher III in a span of five years due to outstanding performance in teaching and designated roles.

Capiz State University –
Dayao, College of St. John –
Roxas, and Colegio De La
Purísima Concepción

Roxas City, Philippines 06/2010 - 03/2013

Part – Time Instructor

- Taught Logic, English, Basic Spanish, Research etc.
- Organized teaching learning process for students
- Guided, monitored and evaluated student learning.

VOLUNTEERING

- Borres Youth Leadership Institute, Inc. (BYLI) with a team, organized programs for youth development centered on leadership.
- Global Institute for Youth Development, Inc. (GIYD) facilitated an online course for young people about sustainable
 development goals.
- Young SouthEast Asian Leadership Institute (YSEALI) developed and proposed projects for the improvement of the chosen community and assisted in the planning of various programs and outreach activities.

EDUCATION

Dev Academy Aotearoa Wellington, New Zealand 08/2023 - 12/2023	New Zealand Certificate in Applied Software Development (Level 6)
Filamer Christian University Roxas City, Capiz, Philippines 05/2013 – 04/2018	Master of Arts in Teaching - Social Sciences (NZQA LEVEL 9)
Sancta Maria Mater et Regina Seminarium Roxas City, Capiz, Philippines 06/2006 - 03/2010	Bachelor of Arts
	Major: Philosophy Minor: English (NZQA LEVEL 6)

TECHNICAL SKILLS



SOFT SKILLS



INTERESTS

I love coding and problem-solving, particularly figuring out how to make my features work. Outside of work, I explore New Zealand's scenic landscapes, enjoy trying new foods, and create memories with my wife. Currently, I'm honing my skills in developing applications with Google Cloud while deepening my expertise in React and Typescript.

REFERENCES

Available upon request